<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!-- Created by Charles Hoffman, CPA: 5/9/2017 9:40:58 AM -->
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:rss='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/'>
   <channel>
      <title>Digital Financial Reporting Concept Arrangement Patterns (2017-05-07)</title>
      <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/rss.xml</link>
      <description>Digital Financial Reporting Concept Arrangement Patterns (2017-05-07)</description>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
      <docs>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/Index.html</docs>
      <generator>Manual</generator>
      <managingEditor>charles.hoffman@me.com (Charles Hoffman)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>charles.hoffman@me.com (Charles Hoffman)</webMaster>
         <item>
            <title>01 - Hierarchy</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/01-Hierarchy/Hierarchy-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A hierarchy information model denotes a hierarchy of concepts with no numeric relations. If no numeric relations exist, then the information model of the component is a hierarchy.  Basically, anything can be modelled as a hierarchy. It is the addition of additional  relations, typically mathematical computations, which turns a hierarchy into some other metapattern.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/01-Hierarchy/Hierarchy-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>02 - Roll Up</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/02-RollUp/RollUp-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A roll up information model computes a total from a set of other concepts. This information model is commonly referred to a roll up, or by the equation A + B = C.  All concepts involved in this information model have the same set of characteristics and all must be numeric.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/02-RollUp/RollUp-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>03 - Roll Forward</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/03-RollForward/RollForward-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A roll forward information model reconciles the balance of a concept between two points in time. This information model is commonly referred to a roll forward or movement analysis or by the equation: beginning balance + changes = ending balance. In this equation period [Axis] is as of two different points in time and the changes occur during the period between those two points in time.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/03-RollForward/RollForward-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>04 - Compound Fact</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/04-CompoundFact/CompoundFact-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A compound fact information model is characterized by the fact that for some set of concepts expressed within some information model; that information model can be expressed over some characteristic expressed as an [Axis]. Basically, it is the [Axis] which provides additional information which makes each information model unique.  For example, the salary information for the directors of an entity is a compound fact.  The salary information is made up of salary, bonuses, director fees and such information must be associated with a specific director to be meaningful and to distinguish, say, one salary from another salary.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/04-CompoundFact/CompoundFact-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>05 - Adjustment</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/05-Adjustment/Adjustment-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>An adjustment information model reconciles an originally stated balance to a restated balance, the adjustment being the total change, between two different report dates.  An adjustment is similar to a roll forward in that it is a reconciliation, however rather than the period [Axis] changing; it is the Report Date [Axis] which changes: originally reported balance + adjustment = restated balance.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/05-Adjustment/Adjustment-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>06 - Variance</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/06-Variance/Variance-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A variance information model reconciles some reporting scenario with another reporting scenario, the variance between reporting scenarios being the variance or changes.  For example, a sales analysis which reconciles the concept sales for the reporting scenarios of actual and budgeted is a variance.  The equation in this case is: actual - budget = variance. But a variance could take other forms such as a variance from forecast, variance from plan, etc.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/06-Variance/Variance-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>07 - Complex Computation</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/07-ComplexComputation/ComplexComputation-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A complex computation information model can be thought of as a hierarchy plus a set of commutations between different concepts within that hierarchy which are more challenging to model than a roll up or roll forward. The type of computations can vary significantly, thus the challenging in modelling.  For example, the computation of earnings per share is a complex computation.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/07-ComplexComputation/ComplexComputation-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>08 - Text Block</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/08-TextBlock/TextBlock-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A text block information model is an information model which contains, by definition, only one concept and that concept expresses what amounts to a narrative or prose as escaped HTML within that one concept. For example, the narrative associated with a set of accounting policies expressed as a list or a table presentation format is a text block. As there is only one concept, there can be no relations within the information model.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/08-TextBlock/TextBlock-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>09 - Grid</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/09-Grid/Grid-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A grid information model is a pseudo metapattern which uses the presentation characteristics of the columns and rows of a table to model information.  Because the grid models presentation information and not business semantics, it cannot be considered a metapattern.  However, the grid is included in this list because the US GAAP Taxonomy uses a grid information model to model the statement of changes in equity.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/09-Grid/Grid-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
         <item>
            <title>10 - RollForwardInfo</title>
            <link>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/10-RollForwardInfo/RollForwardInfo-SampleInstance.xml</link>
            <description>A roll forward info is similar to a roll forward in that it has a beginning and ending balance; however, the numbers do not roll forward.  The pattern is used to disclose the weighted average price rather than an amount.  The data type is always num:perShareItemType.</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 9 May 2017 09:40:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://charleshoffmanCPA.github.io/examples/concept-arrangement-patterns/10-RollForwardInfo/RollForwardInfo-SampleInstance.xml</guid>
         </item>
   </channel>
</rss>
